# **Christopher Paradeise**

(206) 852 9908 chris.paradeise@gmail.com www.github.com/chrisp-dev www.linkedin.com/in/cparadeise

#### **Related Skills**

- ✓ 7+ Years Professional Waterfall & Agile Development with SCRUM
- ✓ 5+ years of Full Stack Javascript MEAN/MERN Stack
- ✓ NodeJS, MongoDB, MySQL, Angular, React, Frontend, Backend, Fullstack
- ✓ Continuously learning and creating with new technologies
- ✓ Strong Creative Problem Solving Skills

### Education

Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp - 2020 Trilogy & University of Washington BBA Information Systems - 2012 University of Wisconsin Eau Claire

## **Professional Experiences**

Software Engineer, Affirma Consulting December 2018 - February 2019, Bellevue, WA

- ★ Built Find and Replace feature for large dataset ETL using C# and Angular
- $\bigstar$  Drastically improved the onboarding process for new developers on small team of 4
- ★ Helped migrate application from Angular v2 to Angular v6 as well as incorporated RXJS Observables into our own services

Software Engineer, Vanson Technology Services January - July 2018, Bloomington, MN

- ★ Developed upon 20 year old ECommerce platform over 7 months
- ★ Team Lead for Tony Awards 2018 Official Game Angular + ColdFusion + AWS
- ★ Lead the effort to redesign user interface for half a dozen clients including a complete rebrand for Radisson Hotel Rewards

Software Engineer, DTN June - December 2017, Burnsville, MN

- ★ Increased performance of MapServer(C programming language) WebService API for NavBlue
- ★ Created Database functions in PostgreSQL combined with Python handling API requests

which reported 70% time cost reduction from previous methods

★ Created new analytics from server log files developing with ElasticSearch 5.5

Associate Software Engineer, Fortive August 2015 - March 2017, Oakdale, MN

- ★ Designed and developed brand new solutions using the MEAN/MERN stacks consuming data from various APIs written in C#
- ★ Created a React App for a Remote Hardware Configuration/Testing tool interfacing with embedded firmware devices installed on 100+ Alameida County Transit vehicles

Software Developer 1, Imagetrend April 2014 - July 2015, Lakeville, MN

- ★ Pair programmed an offline-first, mobile-first, cross-browser compatible health inspections web application for Orange County Health Services (AngularJS/C#.NET)
- ★ Developed Front and Backend for Live Bidding Application and Leaderboard display for CAT Auction Services (AngularJS/Bootstrap/ColdFusion8-9)

#### **Profile**

Cheers! I am Chris Paradeise /paradise/, a hard-working, dedicated to learning, Software Engineer. I have spent the last decade building up my development skills by earning a Bachelors in Information Systems at the University of Wisconsin Eau Claire, as well as working for successful companies, small and large, focusing on improving the lives of their clients through software development efforts. I just recently finished the Fullstack JavaScript Web Developer Bootcamp through Trilogy and UW. I have had the opportunity to learn how to succeed in a professional environment. I have been lucky to learn AngularJS alongside others, pair programming greenfield, mobile-first applications. I have received much greater understanding of the Agile development process. Being able to teach and learn from teaching others is where I have gained the most knowledge. I love seeing others learn, whether I'm there to guide them or not. I take pride in being a valuable participant on a team of equally passionate engineers and designers and visionaries. I am currently seeking a new position in the tech field as a Fullstack or Frontend Web Developer. Thank you for taking the time to learn about my background and skills, be well.